hey everyone welcome back to this Tosca
automation playlist and today we are
going to discuss about another
interesting topic
so during automation of any web
application it is very important to
clear all the old cache which is stored
in the browser while you're automating
or running your executions inside your
browser right so you always want to
start fresh uh in your browser and you
want to delete all the cache so this is
one of the prerequisite steps which we
follow uh while executing any particular
test case or automating any particular
application right because uh there could
be some data which is left over and
which might affect your executions or
your automation
so in order to clear cache from the
browser right uh you can do it manually
from the Chrome browser right so if you
go into the Chrome browser
and on the right hand side if you go
into the settings you go into more tools
and then there is an option for clear
browsing data right and you can select
cased image and files you can also
delete the browser history you can also
go into advanced and select others and
then click on clear data to completely
clear the cache right
so this is the manual way of doing it
now if you want to do it automatically
through your automation Tool uh so we
are working in Tosca and Tosca provides
a t-box automation module which we have
already looked into which is called the
t-box Start program so using this debug
Start program we can clear the cache
from any browser okay so in this
particular uh video I'm going to show
you how you can clear cache from the
Chrome browser you can apply the same
method for any other browser like IE or
Firefox
so let's go ahead and create a test case
here and I'm going to name it here
Chrome cache
okay and as I said I will be using the
t-box automation module which is called
the t-box Start program
okay and in this ebook Start program we
are going to open the command prompt
okay so we are going to type CMD here in
the path okay and then we are going to
pass a lot of different arguments into
this okay so we'll be starting off by
putting slash C so which means it will
be running a particular command okay
and then in the next argument we are
going to give that command which is the
Del command Okay Del means the delete
command after this we need to pass some
parameters for this delete command okay
so we'll be passing slash Q
and then we'll be passing slash S
and then slash F
okay so these are all the arguments
which we need to pass along with the
command okay also we need to pass uh the
exact uh folder path where our cache is
stored for the Chrome browser okay
so by default this will be the location
okay so it will be under your user app
data local Google Chrome user data
default and cache okay so this is the
cache data which is uh stored from the
browser okay so if you have selected any
other folder location for Google Chrome
installation then it will be something
different but uh by default if you have
selected the default location for Chrome
then this will be the path okay
so let's copy this path and then we are
going to
put it as an argument here okay you
should also surround this path with
double quotes just to make sure that uh
this the this slash strands are not
interfering with the actual value okay
so you need to escape uh this special
characters okay
so these are all the arguments which we
need to pass now if you want to
understand what are the different
arguments which we have passed okay so
apart from slash C so all the uh
different Arguments for the delete
command you can open it uh in your
Google Chrome just go and search for
Windows CMD delete okay and this will
give you all the different uh syntax uh
along with the arguments or parameters
which we need to pass okay so if you see
here
um this slash F it Force deletion of
read-only files okay so it forces the
deletion uh it doesn't ask you to delete
or it doesn't ask for any confirmation
before deleting the specified file for
that you need to specify slash P okay
but for automation purpose you should
always use this uh forced lesion and
then slash S so it will delete the
specified files from the current
directory which we have specified okay
it will also display the names of the
files which are being deleted and then
slash queue is for the quiet mode
so it will basically perform the task on
the background okay so that's that's the
quiet mode you can also give uh all the
other attributes if you need to okay but
these are the arguments which we'll be
using uh for our purpose okay
so let's go ahead and run this and let's
check whether it is working or not okay
so I'll run this in scratchbook
and you will see a small black window
which opened uh very fast and it closed
also right so it was showing you all the
files which we deleted so if you've got
lot of caching you could see that
command prompt deleting all those files
in the background okay
but it was pretty quick okay because I
didn't add a lot of cache stored from
the Chrome browser okay
so the test case has passed and if you
just want to make sure whether the cache
was deleted or not go back to that
particular folder and then double click
on cache data okay so the folder will be
empty which means all the cache was
deleted for the Chrome browser okay
so this you can do it for Internet
Explorer or even Firefox okay
you just need to take care of this
particular argument where you are
passing the path of your cache folder
okay
so that's all for this particular video
I hope you enjoyed it and you learned
something new today if you have any
questions leave it in the comments uh do
keep watching for more videos coming up
on Tosca and other automation tools do
not forget to subscribe to our channel
so that you get notified about every
video WE Post
um on a regular basis
so until the next video keep learning
and keep watching